Hello Mike, hey Caio in this lecture
you'll learn how to create and separate
integration tests
from the unit or also known isolated
tests
the goal is to keep the isolated tests
as fast
as possible as they are the primary
feedback mechanism
for developing our applications you
should be able to run those isolated
tests
several times a day without affecting
your productivity
we recommend you to run them on every
tiny code change
as we've been demonstrating in this
course, isolated tests
give us fast and continuous feedback and
also confidence
that our components work as intended
throughout
the development cycle on the other hand
integration tests
give us confidence that our isolated
components
work well when collaborating together
with no mocks
or any other type of test doubles
however
integration tests can be slow when
making API requests
or interacting with databases or the
File system for example
so we don't run integration tests as
often as the unit
or isolated tests but we do run them
often
and of course as part of our continuous
integration pipeline
exactly code should only be merged to
the master branch
if all integration and isolated tests
pass and all those checks should be
automated
to speed up the team collaboration and
avoid bottlenecks
so let's start by creating a new test
target for our cache
integration tests let's name it
EssentialFeed
CacheIntegrationTests
and let's configure the cache
integration tests
scheme
as always we randomize the execution
order
to guarantee there is no dependency
between tests or the order of execution
exactly let's also gather coverage
for the target we are interested the
EssentialFeed
as you can see we now have a new folder
for the integration tests
with an XCTestCase subclass where we
can start adding our integration tests
the idea is to integrate all the cache
model objects
and see how they behave in collaboration
or
in integration exactly so far we've been
testing them in isolation
by using test doubles but now it's time
to see how they behave
when collaborating with real instances
of the production types
awesome and the EssentialFeedAPI
EndToEndTests
that we created in a previous lecture is
also
an integration test target as it
communicates with multiple modules
and even with the Feed API backend
external service we could add the
cache integration tests
in the API end-to-end tests or even
merge them
in a new integration test target, we
could
however we prefer to keep the API and
the Cache module integration test
separate as they are meant to solve
different problems
and integrate distinct components and
services
exactly so let's run the tests make sure
everything's fine
and let's commit alright it builds
successfully the test is passing even
though we have
no tests but it means we have a clean
target
we can start working on exactly
add EssentialFeedCacheIntegration
Tests
target to separate the potentially
slower cache integration tests
from the fast unit or isolated tests
yeah that's it okay let's start with the
simplest task we can
think of and for me it's just trying to
load from an empty cache
sounds good so we need to create our
LocalFeedLoader which is the system
under test
and perform a load operation and expect
to receive a success
result with an empty array of images
if we get a failure we're going to fail
the tests with a nice error message
yep of course now we need to import the
EssentialFeed
module and we need the makeSUT helper
okay so the system under test is the
LocalFeedLoader in collaboration with
a CoreData
FeedStore the big difference from the
cache integration test
and the Core Data isolated tests is that
now we are using
a real File system URL to save
our Core Data models exactly and that's
instead of the /dev/null that we used in
the CoreDataFeedStore that would
operate in memory
yes because in this case we want to hit
the disk
we want to validate that we are actually
creating
artifacts, state, exactly
we are going all the way from the high
level abstraction
down to the most concrete infrastructure
details
and validating the whole chain works
together awesome
but we have some build errors there the
track for memory leaks
is not visible in this target no because
it's in a separate target
we can add this file to the integration
test target
just like we did with the API end-to-end
tests as well
that should do it let's run the tests
passing but I would like to see a
failing test
so we can change the implementation of
the CoreDataFeedStore
to complete with an error for example
just to force an unexpected behavior
that should generate a failing test
there we have it
it works proving that our test is
testing something
awesome let's undo this change run the
test again
it's passing fantastic let's commit
but we've done two things here one we
added this test
and two we included the memory leak
helper in the integration test target
so I would like to break these into two
commits yeah I like that
first we commit just the memory leak
target membership change
so include memory leak tracking helper
in the cache integration test target
and now we can commit the test so Local
FeedLoader
in integration with the CoreDataFeed
Store delivers no items
on empty cache excellent and I like how
we include in the message
both components that collaborate the
LocalFeedLoader
which collaborates with the CoreData
FeedStore so we're not testing just the
behavior
but we want to make sure that we're
talking about specific components
談論特定的組件
integrating with each other exactly
準確地與其他組件整合
okay second test what happens if we have
好，第二個測試，如果我們有
something cached
一些已緩存的東西
so we have artifacts in disk right we
因此我們在磁盤上有產品，對，我們
should be able to load the items
應該能夠載入這些項目
so the load method should deliver items
因此，加載方法應該能交付保存在
saved on separate instances proving that
分開實例的項目，證明我們正在將事物儲存在磁盤上
we are storing things to disk
另一個實例可以從磁盤上獲取該數據
and another instance can fetch that data
並且另一個實例可以獲取這些數據
from disk which also proves
從磁盤上，這也證明，
that we are storing data across
我們正在跨應用程式執行存儲數據
application runs
確實，所以這很重要，因為
exactly so this is important because
這裡，我們創建了兩個分開的
here we're creating two separate
系統測試的實例，一個
instances of the system under test one
專門用於每一次操作，儲存與
specific for each operation saving and
載入的特定實例
loading
裝載
we don't have this in the unit test yes
我們在單元測試中沒有這個
the Core
那個Core
Data unit tests uses an in-memory
資料單元測試使用內存中的
representation of the data
數據表示法
so having two instances would generate
因此，有兩個實例將生成
two separate
兩個分開的
memory spaces completely isolated now in
記憶空間，完全隔離。現在在
integration we can actually save data to
集成中，我們實際上可以將數據保存到
disk
磁盤上
and use another instance to fetch it
並使用另一個實例來提取它
proving that the whole caching dance
證明整個緩存過程
works accordingly, exactly, so to run this
工作正常，確切地說，所以運行這個
test
測試
we have an sut instance to perform the
我們有一個sut實例來執行
save and want to perform the load
儲存並希望進行載入
first we save and we wait for the save
首先我們儲存並等待儲存
to finish then we load
完成然後我們載入
and we check that we got exactly the
然後我們檢查我們是否得到了具有
same feed we saved
與我們儲存的完全相同的飼料
with the other instance but we are using
使用另一個實例，但我們使用
the helper
輔助者
there is also in a separate target so we
也在單獨的目標中，所以我們
also need to add this Feed Cache test
還需要添加這個 Feed Cache 測試
helpers
輔助者
to the Feed Cache integration tests
至 Feed Cache 集成測試
target
目標
but this file uses a symbol that lives
但這個檔案使用一個在
in another file
其他檔案中的符號
so we also need to include the shared
所以我們也需要將共享
test helpers to the integration test
測試輔助者包含至集成測試
target
目標
run test again it's passing fantastic
再次運行測試，通過了，太好了
and again we can first commit the target
再次，我們可以首先提交目標
membership change
會員資格變更
and then commit the test so include
然後提交測試，所以包含
cache test helpers
in the cache integration tests target
在快取整合測試目標中
that's it
就是這樣
let's run the test again oh
讓我們再次執行測試，哦
failing test okay the first test failed
失敗的測試，好的，第一個測試失敗了
and why is that, artifacts, we are leaving
為什麼呢，產品，我們正在離開
Core Data artifacts
Core Data產品
to disk so it affects the first test and
存到磁碟，所以它影響了第一個測試並且
since they run
由於他們執行
in random order sometimes the second
的順序是隨機的，有時第二個
test runs first sometimes it runs after
測試先執行，有時它是後來執行的
so it's a bit unpredictable
所以有點不可預測
okay so we need to clean the state for
好的，所以我們需要在每個
each test run
測試執行中清理狀態
and we can do that with the setUp and
我們可以使用setUp和
tearDown methods
tearDown方法來做到這一點
as we've done before in the setUp we set
就像我們之前在setUp中設定
up an empty store
一個空的存儲
in the tearDown we undo the store side
在tearDown中我們撤消存儲的這邊
effects
影響
so let's add the test helpers simply
所以讓我們簡單地添加測試助手
removing the file from disk let's run
從磁盤上刪除檔案，然後再次執行
again
再次執行
it's passing let's run again just to
它通過了，我們再執行一次就能
make sure it's still passing
確保它仍然通過
okay run a couple of times it is passing
好的，跑了幾次後，它已通過
but again we've done two things here we
但再一次，我們在這裡做了兩件事
added the side-effects cleanup
我們添加了副作用清理
and also the tests so we can break this
還有測試，所以我們可以將此
down into two commits as well
分為兩個提交
I would like to point out that we are
我想指出的是，我們正在
seeing an emerging pattern here
看到一種新的模式
we are forced to do two or more things
我們被迫做兩件或更多事情
because of all the collaboration
這是因為所有的協作
going on with all the components that we
與我們使用的所有組件的交互
use
是的
exactly when we isolate components we
確切地說，當我們隔離組件時，我們
have a cost of integrating them
也需要付出整合它們的成本
and if we don't manage this well we can
如果我們管理不當就會
create a mess in the codebase
在代碼庫中創建混亂
yes so let's first commit the store side
是的，所以讓我們先提交存儲副作用
effects
的清理
cleanup and then we complete the test
然後我們完成測試
sounds good
聽起來很好
so clean up and undo all cache side
所以清理並撤銷所有緩存側
effects
效應
on setUp and tearDown to avoid sharing
在setUp和tearDown時避免共享
state
狀態
between tests
在測試之間
now we can commit the tests so LocalFeed
Loader in integration with the Core Data
Loader 結合了 Core Data
FeedStore
delivers items saved on separate
儲存在分開的
instances
實例中的項目
proving we correctly persist the data
證明我們正確地將數據
models to disk
模型持久化到磁盤上
that's it and again I really like how we
就是這樣，再次我真的很喜歡我們如何
mentioned the LocalFeedLoader
提到了 LocalFeedLoader
in integration with the CoreDataFeed
與 CoreDataFeed
Store and we have some duplication
Store 結合使用，我們已經有了一些重複的
already with the load method so ideally
使用load 方法，所以理想情況下
we should have an expect
我們應該有一個expect
method that can be reused like we've
方法可以像我們
done in other lectures
在其他講座中做的那樣重複使用
like expect the sut to load an empty
比如預期sut載入一個空的
array of images
圖像陣列
exactly despite these being integration
儘管這些是集成測試
tests the refactoring rules
重構規則依舊適用在這
of course apply here as well, exactly we
我們應該把同樣的心血和用心
should have the same level of care
投入在這裡，完全不同我們
regardless if they are integration tests
應該在集成測試中
unit tests
單元測試
isolated tests or production code they
孤立測試或是生產代碼上
are all code we have to maintain
我們都需要進行維護的代碼
and we should keep high standards on the
我們應該對整個
whole codebase
代碼庫保持高標準
absolutely so this other load operation
絕對如此，這個其他的加載操作
should be replaced with the expect
應該用 expect
sut to perform the load to load the
替換為sut來執行負載，以載入
saved
已保存的
feed now we can add the helper
feed，現在我們可以添加助手
as always with nice assertions and
一如既往的進行良好的斷言和
passing the file and line
傳遞檔案與行數
so we can see failures in the right
所以我們可以在正確的
place let's run the tests
位置看到失敗，讓我們運行測試
passing let's commit extract
通過，讓我們提交提取
duplicate load expectations into a
將重複的加載預期轉移至
shared helper method
共享助手方法中
so we proved we can load from an empty
所以我們證明了我們可以從空的
cache we proved we can load
快取中加載，我們證明我們可以從
from a non empty cache even when
一個非空的快取中加載，即使是
created by a separate instance
由單獨的實例創建的
the last test we need is to prove that
我們需要的最後一項測試是證明我們可以
we can override
覆蓋
the items and disk that were saved by a
由單獨的實例保存的磁盤中的項目
separate instance
單獨的實例
and again we have multiple system under
再次，我們在這裡多次測試系統
test instances here
每一個實例都是為特定的操作而設
each one for each specific operation so
每一個具體操作都有一個測試的實例
an sut to perform the first save another
one to perform the last save
進行最後一次儲存的一個
and another one to perform the load so
還有一個進行加載的
we have three objects
所以我們有三個物件
interacting with the File system here
在這裡與文件系統互動
and two models to save
且兩個模型要儲存
the first and the latest and they are
第一個和最新的且它們是
unique exactly if you compare them
精確地說如果你比較它們
they are different so again we want to
它們是不一樣的所以再次我們希望
guarantee
保證
the collaboration of the components
元件之間的協作
within the whole stack
在整個堆疊中
exactly so first we save with the
確實如此，我們首先用
sut to perform the first save then we
sut 來進行第一次儲存，然後我們
save
儲存
another feed with the sut to perform the
另一個 feed 並用 sut 來進行
last save
最後一次儲存
and then we expect to load the latest
然後我們預期加載最新的
one
一個
not the first one or not empty the
不是第一個或不是空的，而是
latest one
最新的一個
let's run the tests passing
讓我們跑過測試
awesome let's commit
太棒了，讓我們提交
so the LocalFeedLoader in integration
所以 LocalFeedLoader 與 CoreDataFeedStore
with the CoreDataFeedStore
的整合
overrides the items saved by separate
會覆寫由單獨
instances
例項儲存的項目
proving we correctly manage the data
證明我們正確管理資料
models on disk
在磁盤上的模型
that's it now that we have all this
就是這樣，現在我們有了所有這些
duplicate save
重複保存
methods yeah we could also extract them
的方法，是的，我們也可以將它們提取出來
into helpers
成為輔助器
save feed with the sut to perform save
用sut儲存feed，進行保存
that sounds wonderful and in this other
那聽起來很棒，而且在這個別的
test we could have the
測試中，我們也可以有
save the first feed with the sut to
使用sut保存第一個feed，
perform the first save
進行第一次保存
and save the latest feed with the sut to
並且保存最新的feed與sut，
perform
進行
the last save that would be much easier
最後一次保存，那將會容易得多
to read and maintain
閱讀和維護
definitely so here it is the helper we
絕對的，所以這就是我們
created the expectation
創建預期的助手
we save the feed with the given loader
我們用給定的加載器保存feed
and we wait
然後我們等待
until the save operation has finished
直到保存操作完成
let's run the tests it's passing ok
讓我們運行測試，好的，它通過了
let's commit so extract
我們來提交，所以，提取
duplicate save operation into a shared
重複的保存操作變成共享
helper method
助手方法
okay we are done with integration tests
好的，我們完成了整合測試
it seems that we have touched only the
看起來我們只接觸了
happy path
what about the error cases well we are
那麼錯誤的情況呢，好的，我們正在
testing
進行測試
all possible scenarios on a component
在單元
level in the unit
或獨立測試裡對組件進行所有可能情境的檢驗
or isolated tests otherwise
否則的話
if we were to test all edge cases in
如果我們把所有邊際情況都放在
integration tests
整合測試裡面去檢驗
the number of cases would grow
會造成測試案例數量
exponentially
成指數性的增長
depending on the number of components
這取決於組件的數量
that participate in the integration
參與了整合的組件數量愈多
right
對吧
the more components the more tests the
組件數量越多，測試與邊際情況就越多
more edge cases
但若在單元裡測試邊際情況，當你把它們組合起來時
but if you test edge cases in the unit
你只需要測試快樂路線，對吧
when you compose them together
舉例來說，我不能在整合層級強制產生錯誤，但是我
you can test only the happy path right
可以在單元層級模擬錯誤，我們已經
for example I cannot force
這樣做過了。例如，在整合階段中我無法強制
an error at the integration level but I
產生錯誤，但我可以在單元層級模擬
can mock
錯誤，而我們已經
an error in the unit level and we have
進行過這樣的操作。精確地說，在整合階段我們
done it
並不使用
exactly here on the integration level we
任何模擬或測試替身，我們使用的是
are not using
真實的
any mocks or test doubles we're using
組件，並且，如果你把所有的
real
測試
components yes and if you move all your
全部移至整合級別，這將
tests
會導致你的
to the integration level that would
測試範圍過於龐大
result in an unmaintainable number of
導致無法維護的測試數量
tests and very slow test times yes
和非常慢的測試時間 是的
we do not recommend that definitely not
我們絕對不建議這種情況
and there are other problems
並且還有其他的問題
in testing only in the integration level
在僅在整合級別進行測試時
for example when there is a failure
例如，當出現失敗時
you have to debug to find out where is
你必須進行調試以找出問題在哪裡
the problem you don't know exactly which
你並不確知哪一個
component
組件
is misbehaving right so it's not a
是在行為不正確，所以這並不是一個
matter of
問題
should I do only unit tests or should I
我應該只做單元測試還是我應該
do only integration tests
只做整合測試
you probably need both but the huge
你可能兩者都需要，但是絕大部分應該是單元測試
majority should be unit tests
所有的邊緣案例都在那裡然後
that's all the edge cases there then
整合所有的組件
integrate all the components
並看看他們一起的行為
and see how they behave together that
這將給你足夠的信心來
will give you enough confidence to move
快速行動，我們希望能快速行動，絕對的。
fast and we want to move fast absolutely
so again we are not mocking anything in
所以再說一遍，我們在
these tests
這些測試中並未模擬任何事情
we've already proved the components work
我們已經證明了組件是可以運作的
in isolation so using mocks here
在孤立中，所以在這裡使用mocks
won't have much value another thing we
並沒有太大的價值，我們還有
can do here
其他的作法
is to just replace the CoreDataFeed
就是直接將CoreDataFeed
Store with the Codable
Store替換成Codable
FeedStore and it should also work
FeedStore，這樣也應該可以運作
let's run the tests boom they pass
讓我們運行測試，成功了
this is amazing and this is possible
這真的太神奇了，而這是可行的
because of the application of powerful
因為我們應用了強大的
principles
原則
like Dependency Inversion, the Liskov
如依賴反轉、Liskov
Substitution Principle
替換原則，
the Interface Segregation Principle
接口分離原則，
Dependency Injection
依賴注入，
and every other principle we have
以及我們所學過的所有原則
studied so far basically
基本上就是這樣
exactly so we have two implementations
因此我們有兩個實作
that behave
行為
exactly the same even though they use
完全相同，即使他們使用
completely different
完全不同
frameworks behind the scenes but
的框架，但由於
since we have those two FeedStore
我們有兩個FeedStore
implementations
實作，
and we just need one for this
而我們只需要一個用於此
application I think we can get rid of
應用程式，我想我們可以去掉
one of them
其中一個
and I believe we should keep the Core
我認為我們應該保留 Core
Data one since it's a more
robust solution yeah I agree exploring
強大的解決方案，是的，我同意探索
Core Data
in future lectures will be much more
在未來的課程中將更有
valuable so
價值，所以
we can discard the CodableFeedStore
我們可以放棄CodableFeedStore
for now
暫且如此
okay I'm removing the production and
好的，我將移除生產和
test code
測試代碼
for the CodableFeedStore
關於CodableFeedStore的
implementation and of course if we want
實現，當然，如果我們想要
to bring back the CodableFeedStore we
將CodableFeedStore帶回來，我們
can do so easily as it will always be in
可以輕易做到，因為它會永遠在
the git history of our repository
我們倉庫的git歷史中
let's run the tests passing let's also
讓我們運行測試，通過，讓我們也
run
運行
the EssentialFeedTests fantastic
EssentialFeedTests，太好了
all good let's commit delete the Codable
一切順利，讓我們提交刪除 Codable
FeedStore
in favor of the CoreDataFeedStore we
選擇CoreDataFeedStore，我們
just need one in this project
只需要一個在這個項目中
if needed of course we can revert this
如果需要的話，我們可以撤銷這個
commit and restore
提交以及恢復
the Codable implementation okay
Codable實現，好的
as a final change I would like to
最後的修改，我想要
configure the CI scheme
配置CI方案
to include the new cache integration
要包括新的cache integration
tests
測試
and of course execute the tests in
並且當然要執行
random order
隨機順序的測試
okay let's run the tests in the CI
好的，讓我們在 CI 中執行這些測試
scheme
方案
that should run for all the targets
這應該要針對所有的目標進行
passing excellent let's commit
驗證成功，讓我們提交
so include the cache integration tests
所以包括cache integration tests
target
目標
in the CI scheme to guarantee we build
在 CI 方案中要確保我們建立
and run
並執行
all cache integration tests as part of
所有的cache integration tests 作為
the continuous integration pipeline
持續整合流程的一部分
and we are all set okay let's have a
一切都準備好了，好的，讓我們看看
look at the logs
日誌
for test times as you can see the unit
對於測試時間，如你所見，單元
tests
測試
55 tests took 0.5 seconds to run
55個測試只花了0.5秒來執行
the API end-to-end tests took 2.6
API 端對端測試花了2.6
seconds to run 1 test right and the
秒來執行1個測試，對於
cache integration tests
that goes all the way storing the Core
完全儲存到 Core
Data artifacts to disk
Data 的文件中
took 0.3 seconds for 3 tests
3個測試用了0.3秒
so you can see how this would not scale
所以你可以看到這樣是無法擴展的
yeah the more integration tests we add
對，我們添加的集成測試越多
the slower your development process will
你的開發進程就會越慢
be
會變慢
exactly when you see these numbers you
確實，當你看到這些數字時，你
need to think about the future
需要去思考未來
clearly 0.5 seconds or 0.3 seconds
顯然，0.5秒或0.3秒
doesn't seem a lot right now but as you
現在看起來不算多，但是你
said can this
說過，這能
scale and the answer is no clearly it
擴展嗎？答案顯然是不能
can't
不能
in large projects, no it will become a
在大型項目中，不，它將成為一個
bottleneck
瓶頸
yes and then most probably developers
對，然後開發人員最可能
will stop
會停止
running the tests we don't want that no
執行測試，我們不希望這樣，不
we want the unit tests to be part of the
我們希望單元測試成為工作流程的一部分
workflow
工作流程的一部分
we want to run them several times a
我們希望每分鐘執行它們好幾次
minute we want it to take
我們希望不管有多少測試
seconds regardless of how many tests you
我們希望它只需要
have exactly
幾秒鐘，確實
as the tests start becoming a bottleneck
當測試開始成為瓶頸時
we need to find ways to speed it up
我們需要找到加快的方法
proactivity is the word we're looking
我們在尋找的詞匯是積極性
for here
在這裡
so separating integration tests from
所以分離整合測試與
unit tests may be mandatory
單元測試可能是必須的
as you grow your application and your
當你擴大應用程序和你的
development team
開發團隊時
that's it for this lecture remember to
這次講座到此結束，記住要
separate integration tests from the unit
將整合測試從單元
or isolated tests
或孤立的測試中分離出來
when there is a performance impact on
當對你的生產力造成影響時
your productivity
也要持續度量建造和測試
also continuously measure build and test
時間以避免瓶頸
times to avoid bottlenecks
在開發流程中，我們完成了Persistence
in the development process and we are
模塊很棒，我們將在
done with the Persistence
下一堂講座見到大家
module awesome we'll see you all in the
非常感謝，我們在
next lecture
下次講座見
bye y'all, see ya
再見，我們下次見